

Alessandro Bagnoli

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · BACKEN

Riccione (RN), Italy

□ (+39) 3391580201 | 🗷 alessandro.bagnoli4@gmail.com | 🖸 AlessandroBagnoli | 🛅 alessandro-bagnoli

"Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic."

Summary.

Currently Backend Developer at OverIT. 3+ years experience in backend development on Java environments and frameworks, with curiosity in exploring also the infrastructural side of the solutions I work on. Interested in devising and applying better methods of solving challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools on the backend side when needed.

Work Experience ____

OverIT

Riccione (RN), Italy - Full remote

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

October 2021 - Today

Backend Development and maintenance of custom web applications exposing REST APIs, with a strong focus on unit and functional testing. Main technologies involved:

- Java 8
- Maven as build tool
- Spring Framework
- Hibernate with Spring Data for persistency operations
- JUnit and Mockito as testing frameworks
- WildFly as application server
- ActiveMQ as message broker for asynch communication between application modules
- · Git with Gitflow for versioning

I-Tel Riccione (RN), Italy

BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

August 2018 - October 2021

Requirements analysis, development, deployment and maintenance of the backend of two of the company's products:

- · An automatic recall system asking the targeted people for confirmation or cancellation of health care bookings.
- A system for reporting clock-in/out, absences, shifts, holidays and leave for employees of client companies via various channels such as IVR and mobile applications, levaraging the integration with the client's existing HR management systems.

I was also responsible for the design and implementation of custom projects and middleware required for integration with external backend systems. During my last year at I-Tel I started studying and working on the migration of one of the two products from the company's proprietary development platform to a new modular and distributed architecture, based on well-known frameworks such as Spring and Hibernate. Main technologies involved:

- Java version 8 and 11
- SVN and Git as version control systems
- PostgreSQL as relational DBMS
- Tomcat as application server
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Asterisk as SIP server integrated to PBX / voice gateway for the VoIP part of the developed applications}$
- Linux CentOS / RHEL as operating systems used for the projects' installation in production environment.

Education

Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna Master's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering

Cesena (FC), Italia

December 2015 - July 2018

• Final Evaluation: 106/110

Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna

Cesena (FC), Italia

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

September 2012 - December 2015

• Final Evaluation: 105/110

Certifications

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

CREDENTIAL ID: EC7RD6TJEJ411W59